[people cheering]
[Chinatsu] Okay.
EIMEI
If he wins, I'll ask him...
to the aquarium.
[opening theme song playing]
BLUE BOX
EPISODE 5
AQUARIUM
[both grunting]
[Kishi] One point.
I can't afford to make any mistakes.
If I don't win this point...
[grunts]
[gasps]
[Kishi groans]
[referee] In! Game!
- [crowd cheering]
- [pants]
[Taiki] That was close.
If he'd gone for a push shot,
I wouldn't have made it.
SHIMOTOMI
[pants] Huh?
- Rematch?
- You got it.
Next time that we practice,
I'll come to Eimei.
Yeah, please do.
Oh, I'll be there!
Make sure to check
when girls' basketball's practicing!
Come on! [grunts]
- He's leaving with his head held high.
- You think so?
He's not one to show it,
but I bet he's feeling the loss.
[Nishida] It's really too bad, Taiki.
[laughs]
If only you'd managed
to beat The Great Nishida,
you could've won it all.
There's still the prefectural qualifiers,
don't giveth up the fight,
young squire! [laughs]
Adieu!
Kyo,
I think Nishida is just not my cup of tea.
Well, regardless of how he acts,
he's still one
of the second-years' top players.
- [Hina] Oh, hey, Two-ki!
- Hm?
Well, you got second, so you're Two-ki!
Don't start giving me nicknames.
Hopefully, next time, you'll be One-ki!
That isn't any better!
[Hina] I heard all about it!
Sounds like you put up quite the fight,
especially for a first-year!
And that's pretty good! For you, anyway.
Why are you being such a butt?
You have a shot at nationals, right?
[Taiki] Exactly.
- So leading up to that, I have to...
- [phone chimes]
[screams]
WANNA GO TO THE AQUARIUM TOMORROW?
IT'S OKAY IF YOU'RE TOO TIRED!
[exclaims, chokes]
[Kyo] Breathe, dude.
Taiki, when did the two of you
get to be so close?
[Taiki] Huh?
Oh. Well... We are...
- [Kyo] I asked her to do it.
- [Hina] Huh?
Chinatsu happened to be at the gym,
and was watching the match.
[Taiki] For real?
A deal was struck that
if your opponent won,
then he would get introduced to Chinatsu.
And I said, if you won,
she should take you out somewhere.
[gasps softly]
It'll be your very first date!
[Taiki] Da...
[Hina] Well done!
Ah, no way.
I'm sure she only asked me
'cause Kyo made her!
You wouldn't go to the aquarium
with someone
just because of something like that.
- [Niina] Hina!
- Oh.
[Hina] This'll be
your first date ever Taiki,
so you better make sure
you're wearing clean clothes!
That was only...
You got this!
[Hina] Would you look at that.
He didn't waste any time.
- Good for him! Good for him!
- Hm?
Huh?
- Are you upset about something?
- What?
Am I?
I might've put on half a kilo?
[Niina] Yeah, no wonder you're pissed.
[grunting]
I can't go inside yet!
Oh, I know!
Chinatsu is just doing something nice
for me because we live together.
There's absolutely no deeper meaning
to be found here!
[grunts]
Huh.
- Quit messing around and get inside.
- Got it.
[man on TV] Do you know
any good restaurants?
Huh? Where is Chinatsu?
She went up to her room already.
She did?
I was hoping to see her, but I guess not.
TAIKI
FIELD GUIDE TO CREATURES
OCEANS
Porcupine fish have 350 to 400 spines.
A jellyfish's body
is made up of 95% water.
[groans]
Kyo, that helpful jerk!
Why didn't he suggest she take me out
in a month, so I can prepare?
[amusing music playing]
SPRING STYLING
And I have absolutely no idea
what I'm supposed to wear.
I wonder what Chinatsu's going to wear.
I'd love to see her in a dress.
Chinatsu in a dress.
No! No expectations.
This is not a date.
This is more like...
like a family outing or something.
- [thudding]
- [gasps]
Huh?
CHINATSU
She's... still awake.
[heart beating]
Oh, man.
This is getting my hopes up too high.
But I can't help it.
- [birds chirping]
- [alarm beeping]
[alarm stops]
[groans]
SATURDAY
I overslept!
I'm leaving!
Crap, and on a day like today.
How can I wake up early
every day, except today?
[pants]
Calm down. I need to calm down.
This is not a date.
Are you okay?
[exclaims]
[Taiki] Thank you for asking.
- Is something wrong?
- Huh? No.
[Taiki] She's wearing a dress.
[happy guitar music playing]
Hey, Taiki, this way!
- [Taiki grunts]
- Fishies, fishies, fishies! Yay!
[Taiki] It seems like
she's more cheerful than usual.
I haven't seen her like this before.
I kept telling myself
not to expect anything,
but maybe it's okay
to think of this as a date.
So cute!
[Taiki] Yes, you are!
I do wonder...
what she really thinks
about us being out together.
Oh, I just wanted to go
to the aquarium, that's all!
[Taiki] Very possible.
I can't believe you made me
a prize to be won in a bet.
You'll pay for that.
[Taiki] I don't think she'd say that,
but she wouldn't be wrong.
Well, so, what do you think?
[Chinatsu] Taiki!
[camera clicks]
- Huh?
- Looks great.
[Taiki grunts] Why'd you take
a picture of me?
[Chinatsu] For the memories!
[Taiki] Please delete it.
Not gonna happen.
We going to need something
to remember this day by!
[exclaims]
[Taiki] I wish that was me.
If today's just about the aquarium
for her, I'll never recover.
[both gasp]
[Chinatsu] They're so plump and cute...
[Taiki] Plump?
[Chinatsu] I just wanna squish one.
[Taiki] I wonder
if they're cool to the touch.
[grunts] Don't look directly at her!
Mom, look, over here!
[woman] Masaki, watch out!
Excuse me.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh.
It's all right.
See you!
[Taiki] I'd love to
come back here as a couple.
But I'm not ready
to tell her how I feel yet.
I've got a long way to go till nationals.
And confessing your love
to your housemate?
It could make things
uncomfortable at home.
We should be getting back, huh?
Uh. Hold on!
Why is she always grabbing me?
- Oh. What's up?
- Sorry.
The truth is,
there's something
I wanted to talk to you about today.
Huh?
In this setting?
Right here, right now?
Could she...
What is it?
Does she feel the same...
Taiki it's just...
I'm sorry.
[Taiki] Uh...
Um, sorry about?
[Chinatsu] The other day.
I said you still have next year
and the year after that.
Wha...
Uh... Oh!
You're sorry for that?
I said it knowing how hard
you've been working lately.
That wasn't
a very thoughtful thing to say.
[Taiki] Of course.
She doesn't know that
I overheard her the other day.
[Chinatsu] And we didn't have
a chance to talk after.
But, I don't want to continue
living together with you, just...
letting things fester,
and never talking about them.
So I wanted to apologize to you today.
[sighs]
[Taiki] So that's what this was about.
I can't believe I even thought
this might be a date.
So this was all to reward me,
and apologize to me then?
She didn't need to apologize.
It actually lit a fire under me.
Chinatsu, I think
you may have overthought it.
[gasps softly]
[chuckles] I don't tend
to hold onto things like that.
And I think that you have
a really valid perspective.
I'm honestly a little bit surprised
that you've been worrying yourself
about this for the last week.
Then again...
it makes sense to feel that anxious
while living in a stranger's home.
Let's see...
- Oh, there it is.
- [phone chimes]
[Chinatsu exclaims]
MR. CAPE
DOWNLOAD
If you ever feel uncomfortable
living at our house,
- or if you wanna tell me something...
- [phone chimes]
HEY! HEY!
...just send me this sticker.
That'll be the signal.
[chuckles] When I get it,
I'll come and listen to you.
CHINATSU KANO
HEY, HEY
[gasping]
Wait, what is it?
[Taiki gasps softly]
Do you wanna tell me something?
[Chinatsu] Hmm...
Yes, I do.
Taiki Inomata. You're a good housemate.
[Taiki] A good housemate?
[groans]
For now...
I guess that'll do.
[feel-good music playing]
[Kyo] You're chowin' down.
I'm a guy who's trying
to make it to nationals.
[gulps, munching voraciously]
Something's telling me you had
a good time at the aquarium, huh?
[exclaims]
[Taiki] It was fun.
Thanks for doing that.
No prob.
I've been thinking about this a while.
[Taiki] Hm?
I understand why you can't be
the one to instigate things...
but what would you do if Chinatsu...
liked you?
[exclaims] Wha... Me? Huh?
[Kyo] It's a possibility.
That... is... not... I... Oh...
I didn't know that.
[gasps softly]
[gasps]
[giggles]
[exclaims]
If it's a possibility,
I would love to date her.
Yeah, I got that, dude.
[Hina] Hey, Smiley Face.
You gotta resubmit this.
Hina.
You can't live in la-la land.
Check things before you turn 'em in.
And you were grinning
like a dork through the whole class.
I was not.
[Hina groans]
That's the face, right there!
The one you're doing now!
[Taiki] Quit it!
[Hina] That looks of yours bothers me.
Ah, quit it already.
It's gonna get all crinkled!
- [Hina] It's not mine, I don't care.
- Hey!
You really do need
to come back to earth, though.
Qualifiers are around the corner.
I know that!
The qualifiers...
will have lots of people
who won regional preliminaries.
I gotta stay focused.
Thanks for the food.
Which school is strongest in badminton?
Sajikawa. They've got
the best badminton team around.
SAJIKAWA
They took it all at nationals last year.
They're beyond prefectures,
they're national-level.
If we don't manage to beat Sajikawa,
we have no chance at nationals.
So then, go and get creamed!
[Taiki] It's a given that I'll lose?
And what's going on with you, Hina?
You have qualifiers, too.
[chuckles] Look at who
you're worrying about.
I'm the great Hina Chono.
"Easy Breezy's" my middle name!
This is when it starts...
- Miss Chono!
- Huh?
[Taiki]
That's the rhythmic gymnastics advisor.
[coach] Splendid timing!
This is Shibata from the local newspaper.
As one of the top athletes
going to nationals,
I'd love an interview.
It would be my pleasure.
[chuckles smugly]
[Taiki] Ten points for the smug face.
OPINION BOX
[Shibata] I actually
saw you compete last year.
[Hina] Oh, really, you did?
[Taiki] You know, It feels pretty weird.
[Kyo] Hm?
Well, seeing Sajikawa compete,
it's impossible
not to be impressed by them, right?
Yeah.
[Taiki] Hina's one of those people
you get impressed by at tournaments.
But she's just a normal kid.
[Kyo] Of course she is.
Yes, exactly right.
[Kyo] She's just a normal kid.
USHINUMA OSTEOPATHIC CLINIC
Whoa, I can move so much better.
[doctor] Make sure you keep stretching.
[Hina] Thank you, Doctor!
Huh?
[gasps softly]
Good evening.
[receptionist] Miss Kano,
your bill is 27.50.
All right.
[Hina] I didn't know
Chinatsu came to this clinic!
I'll have to tell Taiki.
[gasps]
Oh Hina, do you, uh... do treatment here?
[Hina] Uh, it's just for upkeep!
Injuries are scary, huh?
[Hina] I think he has a chance with her.
Hm.
Come to think of it,
do you know Taiki
sprained his ankle in middle school?
He did?
Uh-huh. It was on a school camping trip.
We were climbing up a mountain.
I slipped, and was about to fall,
but Taiki caught me.
He was the one who ended up getting hurt.
He had to sit out at practice
for almost an entire week.
Seeing all that, I yelled at him a little.
[sighs] To know that someone
got injured because of me,
and had to sit out of their club practices
made me feel like crap.
But then he said...
It's my fault
that my reflexes aren't better.
Now I have something to work on.
He really is a hopeless badminton nerd,
don't ya think, Chinatsu?
[exclaims softly]
But he's got good qualities!
He'll sacrifice himself
for the sake of others!
How about that, Taiki?
I raised your stock with her!
Hina, do you...
Do I...
Oh.
Um...
No, nothing.
[receptionist] Miss Chono,
your total is also 27.50.
[Hina] Okay!
[unzipping]
[rain pattering]
Oh, shoot. Forgot my umbrella.
- You can use this one if you want.
- Huh?
But what about you?
Oh, I realized I already had
a foldable one in here.
[opens umbrella]
All right, get home safe then.
Thanks so much, Chinatsu.
Hm.
She's so prepared.
She's kind, and cute, and good at sports.
I kinda hope she has some weird fetish.
- Miss Kano!
- Hm?
Did she leave already?
Something the matter, ma'am?
She left her phone behind.
I can get it to her.
She lent me her umbrella after all.
It's the least I can do.
Oh!
Found her!
[gasps]
INOMATA
- Welcome back.
- You going somewhere?
The store, I thought, but... Mm.
I guess I won't go, then.
I would've gone on my way back
if you'd asked.
[breath shudders]
[rain falling heavily]
[closing theme song playing]